GIOVANNA AVEIRO FULL STACK DEVELOPER

/glrta 🛅

github/glrta

giovanna.netlify.app

glrta@pm.me ☑

+44 7490 215 071 📞

about

A curious and versatile junior full stack developer with a background in humanities, a knack for design and user experience, who decided to become the change she wants to see in the tech industry.

skills & stack

Responsive design
Test Driven Development
Accessibility
Agile Methodology
Pair-programming

frontend

HTML5 CSS3 / SASS Javascript ReactJS

Styled Components Material UI

backend

Node.js Express.js REST API PostgreSQL

test

Tape / nyc

Jest

Supertest

Cypress Codecov

React Testing Library

-tools

Netlify dev

Heroku

Travis CI

Figma

Git / Jira

experience

FOUNDERS AND CODERS

Full stack developer

- Dedicating 4 months to this **highly selective full stack Javascript** development programme focused on weekly **project-based sprints**.

ISAAC NEWTON INSTITUE

Administrative Assistant

Nov 2018 - Feb 2020, Cambridge

March 2020 - present, London

- Created and implemented a new event management system that **streamlined workflow**, **reduced workload** and **facilitated communication** across teams.
- Achieved **Bronze**, **Silver** and **Gold awards** as part of the Green Impact Challenge.

- Organised 20+ week-long workshops per year for junior to senior mathematicians.

selected projects

ENTERPRISE ADVENTURE Developer / UX/Ui Lead

Jun 2020, London

A web app for non-profit Teach a Man to Fish focused on empowering young people in Asia, Africa and Latin America with skills to succeed in school, work and life.

- Coordinated user testing, revised product design, ensured accessibility.
- Designed and built over **three week-long sprints** following **Agile workflow**.

technologies: react, styled components, airtable, netlify dev, jest, material ui

qithub.com/fac19/teach-fish-frontend

BECHDEL AND BEYOND Developer / QA Lead

May 2020, London

A community-driven app that allows users to rate and find films based on gender representation on screen and behind the scenes.

- Ensured over 90% API/FE test coverage and user journeys tested with Cypress.

technologies: node.js, express, postgreSQL, react, tape, jest, cypress, travis

github.com/fac19/Bechdel-Beyond

github.com/fac19/Bechdel-Beyond-backend

education

COMMUNICATION AND SEMIOTICS

Master's degree, 2013 - 2015 PUC-SP, São Paulo - Brazil

Dissertation about Brazilian magazines for women. Conducted **discussion groups** and **interviews with readers**.

SOCIAL SCIENCES

BA degree, 2007 - 2011 UFSC, Florianópolis - Brazil

volunteer

CODEBAR MEETUP

Coding Coach May 2020 - present, London

courses

FRONT-END DEVELOPMENT

Jun - Sep 2019 General Assembly, London HTML, CSS and responsive design.